Python doesn't really know how to represent this generator in any other way. It doesn't know what's in it until you start looping through it.
The other cool thing about generators is they don't necessarily have to have an end, right?
The structure is not in memory, so you can kind of be a little loosey goosey about it.
A good way to think about generators is, you know, the list has all the items in it,
but a generator and only knows where it is right now, and it knows the very next step.
It has no idea what happened in the past. It's got, you know, some weird amnesia,
and it doesn't really know where it's going in the future besides for the very next step.
So I'll make a little bit more sense.
We talked a little bit about slicing yesterday, but slicing is a way to create sublifts.
From larger lists. So let's say I had my string.
So our string is kind of considered as sequence in Python.
What well my string zero return?
Each.
We also looked at negative slicing. What well my string subscripts negative one return?
exclamation point.
But we also learned that we can provide two numbers into this range.
So let's just say I wanted to return the string, hello.
I can say zero one two three four.
And I would put in position five because just like a range.
These are the first four characters.
Just like range, the second argument to the subscript, it's exclusive.
So it does not include the character that you put in there.
We also know that when you're working with either the first value of the list or the last value of the list,
that the zero is optional gives us the same thing.
So we can put any numbers in here that we want.
It'll give us a new copy of those values from the string.
So doing it with a list.
Renders the same results.
Say I have a list of four items in it.
What will name zero return?
And names negative one.
What's the last item?
What if I wanted the first two items in the list?
What would I put for my second range variable?
First two items would be three.
Oh sorry, two.
I'm sorry, whoever corrected me, you were right.
Because list indexes start at zero.
And is this zero optional or not?
If I wanted to go to the end of the string, I would start at zero one two.
And I would go to four.
So that's the end of my list.
That's the length of it.
Just like what zero is this four optional.
It is because we're going all the way to the end.
One of the cool useful uses for the substring.
So if we have a list, let's say my list names,
and I reassign it to new names.
If I append a new value here,
is it going to change my names list?
Well, yes.
It will, right?
Because all I did is I changed the label here.
I didn't make a new list, right?
I just told Python, these things share a name now.
The point at the same thing.
Can you print out names, too?
It's the same.
So if I quickly wanted to make a copy of my list,
so that I can do some operations on it and not modify the original,
let's say I had my list of names here.
If we started the beginning of a sequence,
and we want to take a slice, is the zero optional?
Yes.
If we go to the end of the sequence,
is the last number, that last value, is that optional?
It is.
So if I put just the colon in here, I'll get a copy of my list.
And now I can say, new names is equal to a copy of my names list.
Sorry, we got new names, but bear with me.
If I append something to this, now, will my names list change?
No.
But my new names, I modified that, right?
Okay.
Let's talk about negative indexing a little bit.
So I had my string here, hello, world.
If I do a negative index one, what do I get?
What about negative index two?
Same where I'm getting here.
Yeah.
So negative one goes to the first last item, negative two,
kind of et cetera, et cetera.
You can get kind of interesting here.
You can go from the end, a length of the string,
to the fourth from the end, and end up with some,
some subset of the string.
You can do the same thing for lists.
You kind of rarely want to get too tricky with the substrings,
because explicit is better than implicit.
You want to be clear, but it's available to you,
and you might see this in Python code.
Okay.
One last argument, let's say I had a list of the numbers from zero to nine.
I can quickly build that list with range, right?
And pass it in to list, and just looking at our list,
the numbers from zero to nine.
We know that this will give us the whole list.
There's one additional third argument to step.
And you can kind of think about it like range.
So the first argument to range, the optional first argument
is the start.
The second argument to range is the end.
What's the third optional argument to range?
It's a step.
Yeah, interval or a step.
So I can do the same thing here,
and say, just give me every other one.
One little other bit of trickery here.
What if the step was negative one?
What do you think that would do?
That's right.
Yeah.
So going through the whole list,
stepping from the end to the beginning.
So just a little bit of trickery there.
Let's say I wanted to go start from the first value.
And let's look at my list again here.
I wanted to start from the first value.
Go to the sixth one.
And then skip every other.
I could use all three of those arguments to range.
And remember that you can slice to get a subset of items from any data type that
maintains an order.
So that would be your list and your tuple.
Can you do this sort of sub sequencing with a dictionary or set?
No, right?
Why?
They're unordered, right?
So if you can't for the data structure,
if you can't subscript it by an index.
And remember, you can do this with a dictionary.
Only if the dictionary has a key of zero.
So that doesn't count.
If you can do this to the data type, then you can take a slice of that.